M. Shiva Matahari Yusda

SUMMARY

Over the past 2 years of hands-on experience in Flutter development, I have developed apps for a range of clients, from small businesses to mid-sized companies. Some of the applications I have worked on have been integrated with Third-Party, such as Google Analytics, Google Maps, Firebase, Chatbot AI, Google's ML Kit, etc. Additionally, I have experience in backend development and designed UI/UX for several of my applications. I use the principles of application development with the concept of clean architecture, design patterns, and always looking for the best way when developing applications. I am ready to bring my expertise to contribute and deliver creative and efficient solutions in mobile application development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mobile Developer

PT. Qoin Digital Indonesia

April 2024 – Present Jakarta | WFA

- Integrate Chatbot AI for digitalization checking and live agent customer service.
- Improvement features, bug fixing and enhanced app performance.
- Create Flutter packages, so that if there is a similar application, just use the package to increase the application development process.
- Implement a text recognition algorithm to detect identity card objects using a customized Google ML kit.

Mobile Developer

PT. Venturo Pro Indonesia

August 2023 - Present Malang | On-Site

- Developed payment integration via Xendit using GetX State Management.
- Maintenance Apps for security and improving performance.
- Integration with Third-Party, Google Analytics, Google Maps, Sentry and Crashlytics.
- Developed Youniverse, Komune Camp, Korlantas, and Laziz-NU app for Android and iOS using Flutter technology.
- Collaborated effectively with a diverse team, including Backend, Front-End, QA, and others.

Fullstack Developer

PT. Adma Digital Solusi

July 2022 - August 2023, Surabaya | WFA

- Designed and implemented an algorithm to monitor agricultural processes using the Simple Additive Weighting (SAW) method, providing accurate decision predictions and enhancing operational efficiency.
- Convert Figma designs into fully functional Flutter applications, ensuring pixel-perfect accuracy and seamless user experience.
- Integrate APIs using Bloc state management to enhance application performance and maintain a clean code structure.
- · Collaborate effectively with a diverse team of designers, developers, and stakeholders to deliver

- high-quality projects.
- Test and maintain applications to ensure optimal performance, promptly addressing and fixing any identified bugs.
- Successfully developed E-Commerce and E-Farmer applications, meeting specific client requirements and exceeding user expectations.

Fullstack Developer Matariza Dev Solution

January 2022 - July 2024, Malang | WFA

- Developed a dynamic web-based company profile, a POS application integrated with Bluetooth
 printers for streamlined transactions, and an admin management application for efficient data
 handling and detailed cash flow reporting
 collaborating with cross-functional teams to design system architecture, ensure timely delivery,
 and provide ongoing maintenance and support.
- Developed a Production Inventory Application using Flutter for an intuitive frontend and Laravel for the backend, featuring CRUD functionalities, notifications, and Excel data export, while collaborating with a cross-functional team to ensure timely delivery and ongoing maintenance.
- Designed and developed E-Wallet Application to manage finances, such as recording cash flow in
 and out, doing financial planning, and transferring money. This application is made using Flutter
 with BLoC state management, and web CMS using Laravel which is integrated with Midtrans
 payment gateway.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (S.Tr.Kom.)

Aug 2019 - Aug 2023

State Polytechnic of Malang (GPA: 3.76/4.00)

ADS Digital Partner X Kampus Merdeka

Aug 2022 - Dec 2022

Certified Independent Studies (CGPA: 100/100)

SKILLS

Dart | Flutter | Bitbucket Action | Github | Firebase | Figma | Provider State Management | GetX State Management | Bloc State Management | Communication | Leadership | Time Management | Adaptability | Problem Solving | Teamwork | Creativity | Dependency Injection | GIT | Laravel | SQL | GraphQL | Rest API | Postman